<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post on Statistical and R blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post on Statistical and R blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Start with the data</title>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <link>/post/how-i-check-the-data-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-i-check-the-data-2/</guid>
=======
      <link>/2018/04/12/how-i-check-the-data-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/12/how-i-check-the-data-2/</guid>
>>>>>>> b3a53b4b9d3355725c97b7629b7290493b1feb90
      <description>The distribution of each variableThe multi-test of correlationsAfter verifying that there is no one missprint in the data and before starting the true statistical analysis, I check the distribution of data and relationships between factors.
For this blog article, I use data of air quality available in R.
The distribution of each variableTo see distribution, I use a ggplot.
library(tidyverse)D&amp;lt;-airquality# First time transform data of tidy onesD_tidy&amp;lt;-D %&amp;gt;% tidyr::gather(VAR, value, -Month, -Day) %&amp;gt;% mutate(Time = Month*30.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I check the data</title>
      <link>/post/how-i-check-the-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-i-check-the-data/</guid>
      <description>There are outliers?First step: Outliers and BoxplotSecond step: Outliers, means and standard errorVerify the repeatability of the dataActually I analyse data from a thesis which measure urbanisation’s influence on physicochemical characteristics. The PhD student sample water once by month during 2017 at seven spots around a lake.
I think it is a nice occasion to explain how I check the data when I received them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first article: A not fully crossed design</title>
      <link>/post/my-first-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-first-article/</guid>
      <description>First Step: Check the repeatability of the dataSecond step: Linear mixed models with backward eliminationLinear mixed modelDistribution of model residualsModel selection with backward eliminationFinal modelRandom effectThird and last step: Analyse resultsIn 2015, I published the article: Is oxidative status influenced by dietary carotenoid and physical activity after moult in the great tit (Parus major)? about my first experimentation. In the aim to investigate on the relationship between dietary carotenoids, physical activity and oxidative status, I captured great tits and kept them in aviaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post</title>
      <link>/post/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>It is not easy to start, the first step is the hardest…
I created this site to explain statistical analyses and used of R that I already did.
It is also intended to evolve with my future works.
See you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>